http://www.gadental.org/privacy-policy

Considerations for Reopening Dental Offices
BOT Findings and Interim Recommendations to Reopening Dental Offices
Special Olympics, Special Smiles Program
Healthy Mouth, Healthy Me!
Privacy Notice
This Privacy Notice explains how the Georgia Dental Association (“GDA”) and its subsidiaries, charities and affiliated entities (collectively, “GDA,” “we," “us” or “our”) collect information about you through our website and how this information is then used or disclosed. This Privacy Notice does not apply to websites that do not display or link to this notice or that have their own privacy notices or to information we may collect from you or about you in other ways, including through emails you may send to us.
GDA Contact Information
You may contact us about this Privacy Notice:
Via postal address:
Georgia Dental Association
Attn: General Counsel
7000 Peachtree Dunwoody Rd, Building 17, Suite 200
Atlanta, GA 30328
By email: communications@gadental.org
How We May Use and Disclose Information We Collect About You
The information we collect via our website may be used and disclosed to improve the content of gadental.org and advance the GDA’s mission. For example, the GDA may use this information for purposes such as:
Registering you for, or providing you with information, programs and services you have requested
Processing, fulfilling and following up on your orders or membership application
Providing access to publications
Responding to your emails or online requests
Sending you information you request
Sending and processing surveys and continuing education quizzes
Publishing membership directories and registration lists
Sharing with companies to offer you products and services that may be of interest to you
Sharing your email address with companies to deliver communications on our behalf
Sharing information about you with members and state and local dental societies
Sharing information about you with service providers, vendors and other companies we do business with
Sharing with third parties as required by law
Sharing demographic information for research purposes
Sharing your email address as described below
We collect information such as the internet protocol (IP) address of visitors to our website, aggregate information on what pages users access or visit, user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, and information volunteered by users, including from surveys, purchases and/or registrations. We may collect information about visitors to our website to help measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns. We also may collect the email addresses of those who communicate with us via email. Our system can recognize the identity of individuals who sign in using their usernames and passwords.
With respect to cookies: We use cookies for a number of purposes, including to administer our website and to record session information, such as items that users add to their shopping carts and user-specific information on what pages users access or visit.
Advertising on gadental.org may be served through a vendor that uses IP addresses for purposes such as controlling ad frequency.
The GDA, its subsidiaries, charities, and affiliates may use or disclose individual's contact information and other information about you, such as your occupation, specialty, member status, graduation date and dental school, to alert you to new information, products and services, events and other opportunities. From time to time, we may also make your contact information and other information about you available to other organizations we believe to be reputable, such as companies whose products or services we think you might find interesting. If you register on gadental.org to attend an event, the GDA may provide an attendee list to other attendees and to entities that collaborate with the GDA on the event.
With respect to email addresses: We generally do not knowingly disclose an individual's e-mail address without the individual's express or implied consent outside the GDA, its service providers, subsidiaries and affiliated entities, GDA members, and state and local dental societies. However, we may disclose your e-mail address in certain situations; for example, if you serve in a leadership capacity or if you provide your e-mail address in connection with an event or an attendee list.
The GDA maintains directories of dentists that may include information you submit via our website. These directories are shared with GDA members and state and local dental societies.
The GDA uses an association management database to collect, maintain, use, and share information about member and nonmember dentists who have attended a U.S. dental school, as well as individuals who interact with the GDA. Information in the database is generally accessible to state and local dental societies of the GDA “tripartite.” A “person record” may be created in the database for such dentists and other individuals. For example, a person record may be created when a dentist or other individual interacts with the GDA by becoming a member, purchasing an item or service, attending a meeting, volunteering, attending a continuing education or other course, or communicating with the GDA.
A person record contains information about the individual such as name, contact information, demographics, membership history, a record of purchases and meetings attended, volunteer positions held, and communications with the GDA and state and local dental societies.
Person records are retained indefinitely. The GDA may use a person record for any permissible purpose under the applicable privacy notice. The GDA may use a person record for any permissible purpose if the individual is eligible for membership in the society; however, if the individual is not eligible for membership in the society, the society may use the person record only for registration of the individual at society sponsored meetings, for determining dues owed, for updating the data (e.g., with correct contact information), to assist with order fulfillment, to create de-identified aggregated data solely for internal use, and for any other purpose for which the GDA has provided express written permission. Person records may not be used or disclosed in a way that would violate this gadental.org Privacy Notice.
The GDA may provide delegates’ names and mailing addresses in response to a request from a dental specialty organization. GDA Action publishes delegates’ names, districts, cities and states, as well as information, including gadental.org email addresses, about officers and trustees.
The GDA may share or license information about you to a third party if, in our sole discretion, we believe that it is (1) reasonably necessary to perform a service or deliver a product or publication; (2) authorized by you or as set forth in any applicable agreement (whether express or implied) between you and GDA, or with your consent; (3) permitted under this Privacy Notice; (4) required by statute or regulation; (5) of interest to dentists, dental students, members of the dental team, or consumers of dental services, or (6) in the good-faith belief that such action is appropriate for reasons of security or legal compliance.
If you participate in an activity such as attending or speaking at a program or authoring a publication, information such as your name and photo may be shared via gadental.org or GDA publications.
The GDA also occasionally hires other individuals and entities to provide services on our behalf, including, but not limited to, hosting of online resources, processing credit card transactions, packaging, order fulfillment, answering customer questions about products or services, consulting services, data modeling, printing, sending postal mail and processing membership and event registration. We will provide those companies with information they need to deliver the service. Third parties may collect information such as your IP address that may indicate your online activities over time or across different websites when you use our websites. At this time, this website does not respond to do-not-track signals.
Certain sensitive personal information is protected by security measures (that may include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings security) to protect the information from unauthorized access and use. If such information is disposed of, it will be done securely.
Your Rights and Responsibilities
It is important when you wish to exercise your rights that you contact us via any of the means listed in the first section of this Privacy Notice.
While the GDA takes measures to protect your personal information, no security measure or network is entirely secure. Your password to access gadental.org should be complex and should never be shared with anyone, and should be changed from time to time. After you access gadental.org, you should log off and exit your browser so unauthorized persons cannot access the site.
If you do not want to receive postal mail, telephone calls from us in the future, or if you do not want us to share your contact information in the manner described above, please provide us with your exact name and postal addresses, phone and fax numbers and, if appropriate, GDA membership number to communications@gadental.org. It may take up to four weeks for your opt out to become effective. While we will continue to share information we maintain about you with our service providers, the American Dental Association (“ADA”), GDA subsidiaries and affiliates, and with other state and local dental societies, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that any other specific contact information you so identify is removed from lists we share with other organizations. We have instituted opt-out capabilities to help you avoid receiving unwanted commercial email messages from the GDA. GDA will honor such requests within ten business days.
On request we may provide you with access to information that you submitted via gadental.org, such as certain transaction information (e.g., dates on which you made purchases, amounts and types of purchases), communications that you have directed to our site (e.g., emails, user inquiries), and contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number).
On request we may also offer the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact information, financial information, unique identifiers, transaction information and certain other data.
In addition to the other rights we note in this Privacy Notice, you also have the right to contact the GDA to obtain the following information:
1. What personal information about you the GDA holds;
2. For what purposes does GDA process your information;
3. To what third parties (and in what jurisdictions) has or may the GDA disclose your personal information;
4. How long will your data be maintained by the GDA (and how that period of time has been calculated);
5. How to request correction or deletion of specific portions of your personal data held by the GDA that you believe are incorrect; and
6. The source(s) from which the GDA has obtained your personal data.
You may also contact us at communications@gadental.org if you believe your information is being used improperly.
You may provide consent to additional uses and disclosures; for example, in connection with a product or service offered by the GDA, an affiliated entity, or a third party.
Children's Privacy
We do not knowingly solicit data online from, or market online to children under the age of 13.
More About Our Privacy Practices
With respect to other websites and servers: GDA.org contains links to other websites. We have no control over and take no responsibility for the privacy practices or content of those sites.
We use Doubleclick for Publishers (DFP) Small Business to serve ads on our site.
When users choose to make payments via credit cards, they do so on the website of a third party service provider. We do not store or reuse credit card information unless you have given us your credit card information directly and authorized us to do so.
Changes, Comments and Questions
If our Privacy Notice changes at some time in the future we will post the revised Privacy Notice to our website to notify you, and those changes will be effective on the day that we post the revised privacy notice. The latest version of our Privacy Notice will always be available at gadental.org.
We welcome your comments or questions about our Privacy Notice and privacy practices. If you feel that this site is not following its stated policy, please let us know.
About GDA
GDA Leadership
GDA Team
Contact Us
Find a Dentist
COVID-19
GDA Press Releases and Announcements
COVID-19 in the News
BOT Findings and Interim Recommendations to Reopening Dental Offices
Healthy Mouth, Healthy Me!
"State":"GA"
